Hello friends, welcome to Shayari
and today I am going to share a very good video.
If you do
n't have a health insurance policy, then you
must watch this video. Friends, when it comes to health
insurance policy, every
person wants to have a health
insurance policy and the
way the cost of our
health care is increasing, the cost of its
juice is increasing, so it becomes
very important to have a health insurance policy.
But the thing is that as soon as you
see the health policy of an insurance company, you see
its terms and conditions, then you
see that their hospital expenses,
disease coverage, room charges, devices, ideas,
journalists, reposts, these plans, expenses, all these
things
become clear after sending them, then you think that friend, is
he going to loot somewhere? And then
what do you do, you look at these companies a lot,
some say that this news, some say that it is covered
and in the end, what do you do, they give away the health insurance,
you don't want to take it,
you feel that you don't go for it, so
keeping these things in mind,
when you send this feedback to IRDA, that
type of  If you are confused about this, then
what has IRDAI done? It has launched the Arogya Sanjivani Health
Insurance Policy.
This policy was made on April 1, 2020,
and as the name said, Sanjivani
is Sanjivani Health Insurance for you people. If you do not have health insurance yet, then
you should look at this policy. It is very
well polished.
Now what I mean by this policy is that this
standard polish, you will
buy a policy from any insurance company, all
their terms, conditions, laws, regulations, which are
effective, will remain in it. No
insurance company will be able to change its wording.
Its coverage will be
similar in all insurance companies. If we
talk about the difference, then the only difference will be
in the premium or their hospital
network, which will be in the insurance company.
Hospital network means that
your treatment in those hospitals is done
cashless, you do not have to make any payment.
You can get treatment in other hospitals also,
but you will have to make
payment there. After that, whatever
expenses you incur, you have to claim from the insurance company.
You get the benefit from there.
This is its fast.
Apart from this, wherever you buy the policy from, the
name of the policy will also be Arogya
Sanjivani, then the name of the insurance company will come,
like Sanjivani of Army, Max Bupa
Insurance, Arogya Sanjivani, Star Health
Insurance, Arogya Sanjivani, SBS Senior
Insurance, its name will
start with Arogya Sanjivani, and
hey boys, if we talk about the experts, then
what is there in it, so many terms and
conditions have been fixed by IRDAI, that is
why you have to read the terms and conditions
once, and whatever I will
tell you in this video, even if you do not know then you do not need to do the
terms and conditions with any other insurance company, the
terms and conditions will be the same in all the insurance companies,
you just have to see how is the premium and
how is the service of the insurance company,
you will see only these two things, apart from this, there is
no work no payment option in this policy,
what does payment mean that whenever your
hospital bill comes, then
you will have to make this much payment, that is,
in this policy your payment is 5%, so suppose the
hospital bill is
of 1 lakh then  5 per cent means ₹5000 you have to pay
9500 to the insurance company,
till this your payment in the rest of the insurance is
10 percent or 15 per cent Vincent,
but here your co-payment is
only 5 percent,
apart from this if you do not have any health
insurance policy and
want to buy a health insurance policy for the first time,
you do not know much about health tips, even then
friends,
make this policy thoughtfully so that if it is the first time then
it is a panacea for that and it has
lifetime validity, that is once
you have taken the policy then you can keep renewing it for life
and after this as it is known that
this is not polythene in all the insurance companies,
so what did they do,
they did not implement any kind of rider in it, that no one will be
able to change the insurance company's warranty, otherwise it will happen, the
insurance company will destroy the entire policy of its riders + + + +,
so keep in
mind that you do
not have to keep the rider in it, the policy is absolutely
plain vanilla, it will be
sold to you as it is.  And if we talk about policy holders, then you
can also take an individual policy
and you can also choose the family floater option.
Apart from this, if we talk about the time period, then
you get a time limit of Rs 1 lakh to Rs 5 lakh.
You can take this in the form of a Sardar, that is, if you first
take Rs 1 lakh, then the next time is the beginning,
that is Rs 1.5 lakh, then Rs 209303 can be given as half-baked
subscription. So Meghnad, this
thing has been criticized, so
what has IRDAI done, later they have
given some flexibility on this and the maximum
is Someshwar, the company can increase it as per its own wish. If we
talk about the terms, then it is two, it can be
decided by the company as per its own wish. And
your no-claim bonus is that five percent, which
you keep getting every year, that is, if you
took it from your college in any one year but you do
not make any insurance claim in that year, then the
next year you get five percent additional coverage, that is,
if your policy is of Rs 1 lakh, then the
next year your news will become Rs 105000.
You did not make any claim in the second year also.
So the next year your insurance gets reduced to
Rs 110000 - the money will increase by five percent
and the maximum increase it makes will be up
to fifty percent.
Apart from this, the policy period will be of one year.
After one year, you will have to renew the policy.
Free hospitalization expenses of 1 teaspoon have been included in this policy.
Post hospitalization expenses of
603 rupees have been included. Your 5 percent in copper,
as I told you, is weighted for
existing. If you already have any disease
like diabetes and
something of this type is prescribed, then you will
start getting the claim for those digits only after 48 months. All these insurance
companies and wherever you go, the waiting period for
your SIM will be 48 months. It is not that if
you have seen an insurance company, it has 48 months,
then you can talk about the cover in other companies.
In Sanjeevani, the waiting period will be of 48 months only. If we
talk about cover, then
their midnight treatment is
also covered in this policy.  We
can talk about eligibility, who
can take this policy, so if your age is between 18 years to
65 years, then you
can become a proposer in this policy, that is, the person who proposes and makes the
payment of quality, his
age should be between 18 years to 65
years, apart from this, father
and three children of 3
months and above can be included in the policy,
if there are dependents, then
apart from this, you can get the policy renewed,
but what is 65, WhatsApp and you
can enter the mileage in it, you have reached 65,
after that you can get it renewed,
you can get it renewed till 66 years also,
but the policy of
sustained by 65 years cannot be renewed if
you have crossed this age,
apart from this, what is covered in it, so
all the hospitalization expenses like bank
charges, nursing charges, blood test, ICU
and consultation fees, whatever extra
charges are there for hospitalization,
hospitalized with simple definition, it is the
insurance company that you will get at least  You will have to
stay in the hospital for 24 hours, that is
considered hospitalization, so if it is an
aspiration, then all these considerations which are
charts, are covered up to your time in this policy, Rs.
1 lakh, ₹2000,
₹3000, Chitra Prathameshwar, whatever expenses you have taken up to that
amount, are covered on it,
its room rent is the room rate,
you get it, but keep the maximum here at
₹5000, if you have to get admitted in the hospital, then
here the room rate is ₹10,000, so you can
take a birthday room for 2 percent of 2 lakh, that is, ₹4000 maximum, and if
you want to get admitted in ICU, then you will
get maximum five percent
of 2 lakh, that is, Rs.10000, you get
room rent here, if you have taken the policy instead of 2
lakh, then your time is covered, that goes to
5 lakh rupees, so
what will be the room rent in normal hospitalization  Your maximum should be 4%,
5 lakh or 10,000, but
what they have done is that your maximum
fee cannot be estimated above 5,000, that is,
250 of MS Word or
5,000, whichever is less, you get room
rent, similarly in room rent condition,
you get 5 per cent polling,
but you cannot take it, but
if you are a subscriber
and what all is covered, then cataract is covered,
25 per cent, excluding 40,000, whichever is
less, you get cataract
cover, if you have taken treatment of
1 lakh, then you can get cataract treatment up to 25 thousand,
cataract means cataract in the eye,
if you get it treated, then
you will get 25 percent, excluding time,
or the maximum, you can get up to
40 thousand, that is, only when
robotic surgery is done, all this
What happens after that? There are some
treatments for which 24-hour
hospital stay is not necessary.
In those, the patient is discharged from the hospital even before 24 hours.
Those expenses are
also included in this policy.
Apart from this, Ayush treatment i.e.
Ayurvedic Unani and all these Yoga Unani
Siddha and Homeopathic treatments,
if you want to get them done then you can get them done
provided it should be an authorized hospital, there should be a
little statement center
and it should be for medical purposes.
Spa and this is not available for all, it is
available for medical treatment and in that
too you can get a print pack for the limit of the time you are injured.
Apart from this,
you also get money for dental treatment and plastic surgery, but the
condition for this is that you are not getting this dental
treatment or plastic surgery done for
beauty enhancement or for status purpose,
you are using it for some medical
purpose, in that condition
you get cover. Apart from this, the
limit for ambulance is Rs. 2,000, up
to Rs. 2,000 for a person in space.  Hospitalization, you get the
cost of ambulance treatment,
then from the hospital, as I mentioned,
what happens even before being admitted to the hospital for 30 days, sometimes money is required for treatment
and you can find the answer to this question here as well.
And post-production news is
that even after discharge from that chapter, all the
expenses for treatment of medicines
or
consultation of investigation for seven days are available to you here.
Apart from this, if we talk about other features, then
here you get tax rebate within section-8 days.
Apart from this,
if you purchase online
from some insurance companies, they give you a
discount of five to ten percent for free.
Free policy check is also available in some companies.
If the
age of the insured person is more than 55, then
medical checkup is done and what happens in that? Yes, the
insurance companies take the payment
and the hospital network
hospital is the hospital where this
treatment is done. You have to pay in other hospitals
and later you
can claim updates. Let's talk about the great spirit.
So,
you get a grace period of 30 days for annual premium payment
and there is a grace period of 15 days for the remaining premium payment.
Dress code means that you
get this much additional time to pay the premium
and what is there in it, so there is a waiting
period for these, in that waiting period,
the insurance
company will not bear any of your medical expenses within 30 days of taking the policy, except in case of an accident,
if an accident happens within 30 days and the person has to
go to the hospital, his treatment
starts from the first day itself,
X cover is that, the rest of the coverage
starts only after 30 days,
apart from this, if we talk about this, then
friends, you can take LIC policy and
if you have an existing policy and you
feel that you want to take Sanjeevani for your hair, then
you can post your policy, you can call
it Good Night Fall or i20 Sport,
if you
want to see its premium, friends, then
you can check the premium by going to the website of Will Win Insurance Company.  You
can check the premium for yourself by
taking the details of your family members and a premium calculator will come from there. There are
many ES General
Insurance companies, so it is
difficult for us to compare the premium here,
we are not able to do it, but we will
make a video about one or two companies whose premiums are
very low and the hospital network is also
good, which we will definitely make in the video. So
if you have
not subscribed to this channel, please subscribe to the channel
and click the bell icon
so that as soon as that video comes, you will be
able to watch that video. In it, we will tell you in detail
which insurance company has the
lowest premium for Sanjeevani,
and its help hospital network is also very
good, the service is also good, so that you can
get health insurance from that company, Arogya Sanjeevani. So friends, I hope
you have learned a lot from the video,
so please take 2 seconds and
like the video. If
you have not subscribed to the channel yet,
please
subscribe to the channel. You are going to get very good information
here and before leaving,
definitely click the bell icon.  Click on it so that
as soon as a new video comes, you will get it
back first, so friends, thank you
very much for giving your valuable time in
posting training me.